Michael Longley papers, 1960-2000
Emory University
- Writings by Michael Longley, circa 1966-2001, Series 2; Boxes 16-43; OP1-4
  - Poems,circa 1968-2000, Subseries 2.1; Boxes 16-34; OP1-4
    - Uncollected poems, circa 1968-2000, Subseries 2.1b; Boxes 28-34
      - "Difficulties," MS and TS (Box 30, Folder 16)
      - "Doggerel" [variant title: "Dogpome"] TS (Box 30, Folder 17)
      - "Dragonfly," MS (Box 30, Folder 18)
      - "A Dream of Children, MS (Box 30, Folder 19)
      - "Driving to Crossmaglen, MS [See also Uncollected poems, "Cornelia"] (Box 30, Folder 20)
      - "Dryad [Naiad], TS [See also Uncollected poems, "Curse"] (Box 30, Folder 21)
      - "Dutch Exterior" [See also Uncollected poems, "A Blessing"] (Box 30, Folder 22)
      - "Easter in Belfast," TS (Box 30, Folder 23)
      - "Education," MS [variant title: "Public Elementary"] (Box 30, Folder 24)
      - "Edward Lear at Bikini," MS and TS [variant title: "Edward Lear Redivivus"] (Box 30, Folder 25)
      - "Edward Thomas," TS [See also Uncollected poems, "September"] (Box 30, Folder 26)
      - "Eel Ode," TS (Box 30, Folder 27)
      - "Egg Money," MS (Box 30, Folder 28)
      - "Elegy," MS [See also Uncollected poems, "In Memory of Patrick Kavanagh"] (Box 30, Folder 29)
      - "The Elephant's Nose," MS and TS (Box 30, Folder 30)
      - "The Eleven Plus," TS [variant title: "The Funeral"] (Box 30, Folder 31)
      - "An Enchantress," MS (Box 30, Folder 32)
      - "Encyclopaedia," MS (Box 30, Folder 33)
      - "The End of the War" (Box 30, Folder 34)
      - "Endings," TS [includes "Death-watch" and "Arc de Triomphe"] (Box 30, Folder 35)
      - "Epilogue," MS and TS [variant titles: "Song from the Swedish," "Song 2," "Song Waiting for a Play"] (Box 30, Folder 36)
      - "Even Now" [variant title: "The Traveller"] (Box 30, Folder 37)
      - "Explosion," TS (Box 30, Folder 38)
      - "Extra" (Box 30, Folder 39)
      - "Fanny Hill" [variant title: "On Reading Fanny Hill," "Open House," "Preparations"] [See also Uncollected poems, "Two Poems" (1)] (Box 30, Folder 40)
      - "The Farm" (Box 30, Folder 41)
      - "The Fight of the Churls," MS and TS (Box 30, Folder 42)
      - "The Fireflies," MS (Box 30, Folder 43)
      - "Fireplace" (Box 30, Folder 44)
      - "First Sounds" (Box 30, Folder 45)
      - "Fishing in the Sky" [variant titles: "The Kite," "Love Story"] [See also Subseries 2.1a: Fishing in the Sky, "The Owl and Stormy Petrel;" and Uncollected poems, "Conversations," "Soiree"] (Box 30, Folder 46)
      - "Fledgling" (Box 30, Folder 47)
      - "The Flying Fish" (1) (Box 30, Folder 48)
      - "The Flying Fish" (2), TS (Box 30, Folder 49)
      - "Fly-Past," TS (Box 30, Folder 50)
      - "Foal," MS (Box 30, Folder 51)
      - "Foam" [See Subseries 2.7: Notebooks]
      - "For a Self-Portrait," TS [variant titles: "A Portrait," "Induction," "A Sequence," "Wars"] [includes "The Steam Engine"] [See also Subseries 2.1a: Man Lying on a Wall, "Love Poem;" An Exploded View, "Wounds;" and Uncollected poems, "Mole"] (Box 30, Folder 52)
      - "For Marie Heaney" [variant titles: "Spell," "Spells"] (Box 30, Folder 53)
      - "For My Father," TS (Box 30, Folder 54)
      - "For Percussion and Tin Whistle," MS (Box 30, Folder 55)
      - "The Foreigner," The, TS (Box 30, Folder 56)
      - "Formal," MS and TS (Box 30, Folder 57)
      - "Foxes," The, TS (Box 30, Folder 58)
      - "Frost," TS (Box 30, Folder 59)
      - "Fruit Bowl," The, MS (Box 30, Folder 60)
      - "Genealogy" (Box 31, Folder 1)
      - "Geography" [includes "Ice House," "Lazy Beds"] [See also Uncollected poems, "Ogham Stone"] (Box 31, Folder 2)
      - "Ghosts," MS [variant title: "Roots"] [See also Subseries 2.1a: The Echo Gate, "Second Sight;" Uncollected poems, "St. Elmo's Fire"] (Box 31, Folder 3)
      - "Gifts," MS and TS (Box 31, Folder 4)
      - "Giving the Show Away," TS (Box 31, Folder 5)
      - "Good Friday" [variant title: "Noughts and Crosses"] [See also Uncollected poems, "The Student"] (Box 31, Folder 6)
      - "Grainne O'Malley," MS (Box 31, Folder 7)
      - "Grasshopper," A, TS (Box 31, Folder 8)
      - "Grass of Parnassus," TS (Box 31, Folder 9)
      - "A Great Tradition," MS and TS (Box 31, Folder 10)
      - "The Guelder Rose" (A Wreath for Janis Joplin) (Box 31, Folder 11)
      - "Hallucinations," MS and TS [variant titles: "Becky Painting," "Rebecca Painting," "A Vision"] (Box 31, Folder 12)
      - "Hands," MS and TS (Box 31, Folder 13)
      - "Hare" (Box 31, Folder 14)
      - "The Harpers," TS [variant title: "The Harpists"] (Box 31, Folder 15)
      - "Harvest Thanksgiving," TS (Box 31, Folder 16)
      - "He," MS and TS (Box 31, Folder 17)
      - "The Headland" (Box 31, Folder 18)
      - "Hedgehogs" [variant title: "The Hedgehog"] [See also Uncollected poems, "A Dedication"] (Box 31, Folder 19)
      - "Hinterland," MS [variant title: "Aunts and Uncles"] (Box 31, Folder 20)
      - "Hochmagandy," TS (Box 31, Folder 21)
      - "Hole in the Head," MS and TS (Box 31, Folder 22)
      - "Holland" (Box 31, Folder 23)
      - "Homage to Stephan Mallarme" (Box 31, Folder 24)
      - "Homages" [includes "Ex-champ," "Keaton," "Billie Holiday"], TS (Box 31, Folder 25)
      - "Honeymoon Hotel," MS and TS (Box 31, Folder 26)
      - "Hot & Cold (Homage to Marcel Duchamp)" (Box 31, Folder 27)
      - "Housewife's Testament" (Box 31, Folder 28)
      - "I Am the Hazel-Nut" (Box 31, Folder 29)
      - "In Memoriam Brendan Behan," MS notes (Box 31, Folder 30)
      - "In Memory of Patrick Kavanagh" [Epitaph] [See also Uncollected poems, "Elegy"] (Box 31, Folder 31)
      - "In the Big House," MS and TS [See also Uncollected poems, "Fishing in the Sky" and "Soiree"] (Box 31, Folder 32)
      - "In the Fields," TS (Box 31, Folder 33)
      - "Incident" [variant titles: "Aisling," "Incidents," "Pick-Up"] (Box 31, Folder 34)
      - "Irish," MS [variant titles: "The South," "Closing Time"] [See also Subseries 2.1a: Selected Poems, 1963 – 1980, "Belfast to Dublin"] (Box 31, Folder 35)
      - "Islander," MS and TS (Box 31, Folder 36)
      - "It Used To Be," TS (Box 31, Folder 37)
      - "Janet Quigg's Cat," TS (Box 31, Folder 38)
      - "Lachrymatory," TS (Box 31, Folder 39)
      - "Lady Day," TS [See also Subseries 2.1a: No Continuing City, "Words for Jazz Perhaps;" An Exploded View, "Doctor Jazz;" and Uncollected poems, "Even Now"] (Box 31, Folder 40)
      - "Landscape" (2), MS and TS (Box 31, Folder 41)
      - "Lanugo," MS and TS (Box 31, Folder 42)
      - "Last Bittern," MS and TS (Box 31, Folder 43)
      - "Last Poems," TS (Box 31, Folder 44)
      - "Leaves," TS (Box 31, Folder 45)
      - "Level Pegging" [variant title: "Michael Allen"] (Box 31, Folder 46)
      - "Life-Sentence," MS [See also Uncollected poems, "Punch-Line"] (Box 31, Folder 47)
      - "Limpet" [variant title: "At Low Water"] (Box 31, Folder 48)
      - "Ling," MS and TS [See also Subseries 2.1a: An Exploded View, "Letters: To James Simmons"] (Box 31, Folder 49)
      - "Lip Service" [See also Uncollected poems, "Bulk-buying"] (Box 31, Folder 50)
      - "Lists" [See also Uncollected poems, "Collector's Piece"] (Box 31, Folder 51)
      - "The Lizard," TS (Box 31, Folder 52)
      - "Longley's Spade," TS (Box 31, Folder 53)
      - "Love Elegy," MS (Box 31, Folder 54)
      - "Love Objects," MS and TS [variant title: "Tokens"] (Box 31, Folder 55)
      - "Love Poem" (4), TS (Box 31, Folder 56)
      - "The Lovers," MS (Box 31, Folder 57)
      - "Low Tide," MS (Box 31, Folder 58)
      - "Lullaby," MS and TS (Box 31, Folder 59)
      - "The Maid," MS and TS [See also Subseries 2.1a: Gorse Fires, "Eurycleia"] (Box 31, Folder 60)
      - "Male," MS (Box 31, Folder 61)
      - "The Map," TS (Box 31, Folder 62)
      - "Masters" [includes "Formby," "Keaton," "Billie," "Django"] (Box 31, Folder 63)
      - "A Mayo Sequence," TS (Box 31, Folder 64)
      - "Memo to the Muse," TS (Box 31, Folder 65)
      - "Memory of Holland," MS and TS (Box 31, Folder 66)
      - "Miss World," MS (Box 31, Folder 67)
      - "The Mole" [Birthmark] [See also Subseries 2.1a: Man Lying On a Wall, "Love Poem;" Uncollected poems, "For a Self-Portrait"] (Box 32, Folder 1)
      - "Mother-of-Pearl," TS [See also Uncollected poems, "Pudenda Mulieris"] (Box 32, Folder 2)
      - "Mr G," MS and TS (Box 32, Folder 3)
      - "Mr. Vorster in the Olympic Year," MS and TS (Box 32, Folder 4)
      - "My Father, My Daughter" (Box 32, Folder 5)
      - "My House In the Dunes," TS (Box 32, Folder 6)
      - "My Jewish Great-Grandmother" (Box 32, Folder 7)
      - "My Pillow," TS [variant title: "Pictures on the Pillow"] (Box 32, Folder 8)
      - "Nakedness," MS [variant title: "Visiting"] (Box 32, Folder 9)
      - "The Need for Centaurs," MS and TS (Box 32, Folder 10)
      - "Neighbours," TS (Box 32, Folder 11)
      - "New Orleans" (Box 32, Folder 12)
      - "Newborn" (Box 32, Folder 13)
      - "The Nightingale," TS (Box 32, Folder 14)
      - "A Nightmare" [variant title: "From the Latin"] (Box 32, Folder 15)
      - "The Nightmare Ground," MS fragments [See also Subseries 2.1a: Man Lying on a Wall, "Last Rites"] (Box 32, Folder 16)
      - "The North Wind" (Box 32, Folder 17)
      - "Novels," TS [includes "The Small Hotel," "The Pool," "The Lesson," "The Big House"] (Box 32, Folder 18)
      - "Nursery," MS (Box 32, Folder 19)
      - "An October Sun" [variant titles: "The Thicket;" "The Rainbow"] (Box 32, Folder 20)
      - "Odysseus to the Sirens," TS (Box 32, Folder 21)
      - "Ogham Stone" [See also Uncollected poems, "Geography"] (Box 32, Folder 22)
      - "Oisin in the Land of Eternal Youth" [variant titles: "Oisin in Tir-na-Nog," "Ossian: A Simple Stanza"] (Box 32, Folder 23)
      - "The Old Story," MS and TS (Box 32, Folder 24)
      - "Old Westerns," MS (Box 32, Folder 25)
      - "On Sitting Down to Read Keats's 'On Sitting Down to Read King Lear Once Again' Once Again" (Box 32, Folder 26)
      - "Open House" [See also Uncollected poems, "Fanny Hill"] (Box 32, Folder 27)
      - "Operation" (Box 32, Folder 28)
      - "Ornithology" [variant titles: "Treecreeper," "Picnic"] [includes "Larks," "Swan," "Tree-creeper"] (Box 32, Folder 29)
      - "Orpheus" [variant title: "Orpheus and Eurydice"] (Box 32, Folder 30)
      - "Our Great Indoors" [variant title: "Our Big Indoors"] (Box 32, Folder 31)
      - "The Painters," MS and TS [variant title: "Images"] (Box 32, Folder 32)
      - "A Pair of Spectacles" (Box 32, Folder 33)
      - "Parable," TS (Box 32, Folder 34)
      - "Parents" (Box 32, Folder 35)
      - "Pass," MS (Box 32, Folder 36)
      - "Past" (Box 32, Folder 37)
      - "Patterns" [variant title: "The Feast of Saint Martin"] (Box 32, Folder 38)
      - "Pauline," MS (Box 32, Folder 39)
      - "Peeping Tom" (Box 32, Folder 40)
      - "The Pheasants," TS (Box 32, Folder 41)
      - "Pianola," MS (Box 32, Folder 42)
      - "The Pine Marten," MS and TS (Box 32, Folder 43)
      - "Pizzas and Beer in the Botanic Inn," MS (Box 32, Folder 44)
      - "Poem" (Box 32, Folder 45)
      - "The Poem," MS and TS (Box 32, Folder 46)
      - "Polderland" (Box 32, Folder 47)
      - "Political Epigrams," MS and TS [includes "Belfast to Dublin," "The Phoenix"] (Box 32, Folder 48)
      - "Pot-Hole," MS and TS [See also Uncollected poems, "Geography"] (Box 32, Folder 49)
      - "Preface," TS (Box 32, Folder 50)
      - "Pretending to Be Drunk" [variant title: "Uncles"] (Box 32, Folder 51)
      - "Primitive," MS (Box 32, Folder 52)
      - "Propaganda" (Box 32, Folder 53)
      - "Pudenda Mulieris," MS [See also Uncollected poems, "Mother-of-Pearl"] (Box 32, Folder 54)
      - "Punch-Line," TS [See also Uncollected poems, "Bulk-buying"] (Box 32, Folder 55)
      - "A Question" [See also Subseries 2.1a: Man Lying On a Wall, "Mole"] (Box 32, Folder 56)
      - "Race War," TS (Box 32, Folder 57)
      - "Rain and Grace" [See Subseries 2.7: Notebooks]
      - "Ray From the Sun" TS [with notes on verso about Greek translation by unidentified correspondent] (Box 32, Folder 58)
      - "The Red Door," TS (Box 32, Folder 59)
      - "The Red Wind" [variant title: "Fuchsia"] (Box 33, Folder 1)
      - "Rejectementa" (Box 33, Folder 2)
      - "Relics" [variant title: "The Feast of the Circumcision"] (Box 33, Folder 3)
      - "Relics," [See Uncollected poems: "The Rose Trials"]
      - "Remembrance Day" (2), MS and TS (Box 33, Folder 4)
      - "The Residents," MS and TS (Box 33, Folder 5)
      - "Resistance," MS (Box 33, Folder 6)
      - "Resurrection of Lazarus," TS (Box 33, Folder 7)
      - "Return to Sender," TS (Box 33, Folder 8)
      - "Riddles," MS and TS [variant title: The Man in the Boat] (Box 33, Folder 9)
      - "Ringing Birds," MS and TS (Box 33, Folder 10)
      - "The Room," MS (Box 33, Folder 11)
      - "Rose Madder" (Box 33, Folder 12)
      - "The Rose Trials" (Box 33, Folder 13)
      - "Saboteur," MS and TS (Box 33, Folder 14)
      - "Saint Elmo's Fire" [variant titles: "In the Restaurant," "The Drunk"] [See also Uncollected poems, "Ghosts"] (Box 33, Folder 15)
      - "Saint Francis to the Birds" (Box 33, Folder 16)
      - "Saying It with Flowers," TS (Box 33, Folder 17)
      - "Scale Insects," MS and TS (Box 33, Folder 18)
      - "Scars" (Box 33, Folder 19)
      - "Sea-Change," TS (Box 33, Folder 20)
      - "Self-Contained Flat" [variant title: "Self-Contained Room"] (Box 33, Folder 21)
      - "September," MS [See also Uncollected poems, "Edward Thomas"] (Box 33, Folder 22)
      - "Sequence for My Daughter" [variant title: "Sequence for Rebecca"] (Box 33, Folder 23)
      - "The Sesame Seed," TS (Box 33, Folder 24)
      - "The Sett" (Box 33, Folder 25)
      - "The Shadoof," MS and TS (Box 33, Folder 26)
      - "Shark," MS (Box 33, Folder 27)
      - "Siesta" (Box 33, Folder 28)
      - "Six Love Poems," MS and TS [includes "Soft Target," "Drag-net," "Stretch-marks," "Voice-box," "Check-up," "Leavetakings;" also "Double-barrel," "Word-play"] (Box 33, Folder 29)
      - "The Slave," MS and TS (Box 33, Folder 30)
      - "A Slight Adultery," TS (Box 33, Folder 31)
      - "The Slipping House," MS (Box 33, Folder 32)
      - "Slogans," MS (Box 33, Folder 33)
      - "A Small Hotel" (Box 33, Folder 34)
      - "Soiree" [See also Uncollected poems, "In the Big House," "Fishing in the Sky"] (Box 33, Folder 35)
      - "Solemnly" (Box 33, Folder 36)
      - "Son" (Box 33, Folder 37)
      - "Song at Sixty," annotated TS (Box 33, Folder 38)
      - "Song 1" ["The best condition's being dead"], TS (Box 33, Folder 39)
      - "Song 3" ["Mankind is interrogative"], MS and TS (Box 33, Folder 40)
      - "The Sparrows," TS (Box 33, Folder 41)
      - "Spider," MS (Box 33, Folder 42)
      - "Stairs," MS (Box 33, Folder 43)
      - "The Storm," MS (Box 33, Folder 44)
      - "Stranded Whales," MS [See also Uncollected poems, "Whale"] (Box 33, Folder 45)
      - "The Stranger" (Box 33, Folder 46)
      - "The Strangford Stone," MS and TS (Box 33, Folder 47)
      - "The Student" [variant title: "Ritual"] [See also Uncollected poems, "Good Friday"] (Box 33, Folder 48)
      - "The Swans and the Octopus," TS (Box 33, Folder 49)
      - "Tactics," MS (Box 33, Folder 50)
      - "Tam" (Box 33, Folder 51)
      - "Tchaikovsky in the Rain," TS (Box 33, Folder 52)
      - "Theory: For Michael Allen" (Box 33, Folder 53)
      - "This Room," TS (Box 33, Folder 54)
      - "Three Poems About Birds," TS [includes "Left Behind" [see also "Edward Thomas" and "September"], "Freeze-up"] (Box 33, Folder 55)
      - "To Edna," TS (Box 33, Folder 56)
      - "To George Best On His Comeback," MS notes (Box 33, Folder 57)
      - "To the Muse," TS [variant title: "Comparison"] [See also Uncollected poems, "Race War"] (Box 33, Folder 58)
      - "The Towpath" [variant title: "Coracle"] (Box 33, Folder 59)
      - "Tract," MS and TS (Box 33, Folder 60)
      - "Tra-na-rossan," TS (Box 33, Folder 61)
      - "Translation," MS and TS (Box 33, Folder 62)
      - "Triangle" [variant title: "Two Novels"] [includes "The Lesson," "The Swimming Pool"], TS (Box 33, Folder 63)
      - "The Trout" [variant titles: "Annunciation," "Two Carols"] (Box 33, Folder 64)
      - "Truman Capote and the Kansas City Murders," TS (Box 33, Folder 65)
      - "Tulip" [variant title: "Bitch"] (Box 33, Folder 66)
      - "Two Endings," TS [includes "Death-watch," "Arc de Triomphe"] (Box 34, Folder 1)
      - "Two Epitaphs," MS [includes "Billie Holiday," "George Formby"] (Box 34, Folder 2)
      - "Two Love Poems" [includes "The Rope-Makers," "Dark Glasses"] (Box 34, Folder 3)
      - "Two Love Poems for Edna," MS [includes "Stairs," "In Touch"] (Box 34, Folder 4)
      - "Two Poems" (1) [includes "Homage to Buster Keaton," "Fanny Hill," "Ex-Champ"] (Box 34, Folder 5)
      - "Two Poems" (2) [includes "Celeste," "Image from Propertius"] (Box 34, Folder 6)
      - "Two Postcards" [includes "From the Country," "From Belfast"] (Box 34, Folder 7)
      - "Two's Company," MS (Box 34, Folder 8)
      - "Ulster" [variant title: "Ulster Politics"] (Box 34, Folder 9)
      - "Underneath the Wigan Moon" [variant title: "Epitaph for George Formby"] [See also Uncollected poems, "Old Westerns"] (Box 34, Folder 10)
      - "Vespers," MS (Box 34, Folder 11)
      - "War Baby" [See also Subseries 2.1a: The Ghost Orchid, "Rosemary"] (Box 34, Folder 12)
      - "The Waves," MS and TS (Box 34, Folder 13)
      - "The Weepies," MS (Box 34, Folder 14)
      - "Wet Nurse" (Box 34, Folder 15)
      - "Whale" [See also Uncollected poems, "Stranded Whales"] (Box 34, Folder 16)
      - "Whimbrel" [See also "Ghost Orchid," "Sandpiper"] (Box 34, Folder 17)
      - "Whirlwind" (Box 34, Folder 18)
      - "The White Lake," TS (Box 34, Folder 19)
      - "The White Swallow" [variant title: "A Dream"], TS (Box 34, Folder 20)
      - "Winter," TS (Box 34, Folder 21)
      - "Without Apologies" [includes "Never Anonymously" and "Sleeping on it"], TS (Box 34, Folder 22)
      - "Woman Kicking a Hat" (Box 34, Folder 23)
      - "Woman Speaks-," A, MS (Box 34, Folder 24)
      - "The Word" (Box 34, Folder 25)
      - "Word Play," TS (Box 34, Folder 26)
      - "The Words" (Box 34, Folder 27)
      - "Words for Gaius Valerius Catullus" [variant title: "Fragmenta"] [See also Subseries 2.1a: An Exploded View, "Altera Cithera"] (Box 34, Folder 28)
      - "Words from Belsen" [variant title: "A man speaks"], TS (Box 34, Folder 29)
      - Unidentified manuscripts
      - Unidentified poems and fragments, circa 1967 – 1969 (Box 34, Folder 30)
      - Unidentified poems and fragments, circa 1970 – 1974 (Box 34, Folder 31)
      - Unidentified poems and fragments, circa 1975 – 1976 (Box 34, Folder 32)
      - Unidentified poems and fragments, circa 1977 – 1978 (Box 34, Folder 33)
      - Unidentified poems and fragments, circa 1979 – 1980 (Box 34, Folder 34)
      - Unidentified poems and fragments, circa 1988 – 1991 (Box 34, Folder 35)
      - Unidentified poems and fragments, circa 1991 – 1992 (Box 34, Folder 36)
      - Unidentified poems and fragments, circa 1992 – 2000 (Box 34, Folder 37)
      - Other unidentified poems (Box 34, Folder 38)
  - Prose, Subseries 2.2; Boxes 35-38
    - American Ireland Fund Literary Award (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Arts in Ulster, The (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Blackthorn & Bonsai, or, A Little Brief Authority (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Boat on the River, A [variant title: Remembering the Sixties] (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Brian Ferran [introduction] (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Carr's Loney: A Note on Tom Carr (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Cenotaph of Snow (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Circulars (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Colin Middleton (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - David Crone (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Definition of Poetry (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Donald Hall & Tim Robinson [welcome address] (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - Embarrassed Imagination, The (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - Farewell to Arms, A [reading] (Box 35, Folder 14)
    - Fire in the Window, The: A Response to the Paintings of David Crone (Box 35, Folder 15)
    - First Loves (Box 35, Folder 16)
    - Frogs, The (Box 35, Folder 17)
    - Future of the Bookshop at Queen's, The (Box 35, Folder 18)
    - Galway Kinnell [welcome address] (Box 35, Folder 19)
    - Geoffrey Hill (Box 35, Folder 20)
    - Ghost Orchid, The (Box 35, Folder 21)
    - Going Back to Sources, A [review of Pharoah's Daughter and An Bealach 'na Bhaile] (Box 35, Folder 22)
    - Graduation Address, Queen's University, Belfast, 1995] (Box 35, Folder 23)
    - Group, The (Box 35, Folder 24)
    - Heaney Bash, The (Box 35, Folder 25)
    - Helen Lewis (Box 35, Folder 26)
    - International Writers Conference (Box 35, Folder 27)
    - Interview with Colin Middleton (Box 35, Folder 28)
    - Introduction for Iain Chrichton Smith and Gillian Clarke (Box 35, Folder 29)
    - Introduction for Mary McAleese (Box 35, Folder 30)
    - Jeffrey Morgan [welcome address] (Box 35, Folder 31)
    - John Burnside [welcome address] (Box 35, Folder 32)
    - John Hewitt Award: Frank Ormsby and Estyn Evans Award: Raymond Piper (Box 35, Folder 33)
    - Joseph Brodsky [introduction] (Box 35, Folder 34)
    - Led by the Ear (Box 35, Folder 35)
    - Lisburn Road, The (Box 35, Folder 36)
    - Louis MacNeice (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Louis MacNeice (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Love of Strangers, The [address for Brian Keenan] (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Medbh McGuckian's Poetry (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Mummers, The (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - My Protestant Education (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Ma Wee Shpake (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - New Ulster, A (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - The Nowhere Birds by Catriona O'Reilly [blurb] (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Obituary: Jack McCann (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Old Man from Dundee, The (Some Thoughts on Rhyme) (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Oxford Book of Ireland, The, edited by Patricia Craig [launch speech] (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - Patricia Craig (Box 36, Folder 13)
    - Patterns and Parables: The Paintings of Brian Ferran [Myth / The Tain] (Box 36, Folder 14)
    - Paul Clark: An Appreciation (Box 36, Folder 15)
    - Perpetual One-Night Stand, A: Some Thoughts on Jazz and Poetry (Box 36, Folder 16)
    - Playthings for the Soul: The Art of Felim Egan (Box 36, Folder 17)
    - Preface [re: The Burren] (Box 36, Folder 18)
    - Preview, Northern Ireland, wk. 46 (Box 36, Folder 19)
    - Propertius (Box 36, Folder 20)
    - Ready for the Stars (Box 36, Folder 21)
    - Remembering Sheila [memorial speech for Sheila Smyth] (Box 36, Folder 22)
    - Review of Ariel, by Sylvia Plath (Box 36, Folder 23)
    - Review of The Collected Poems of John Hewitt (Box 36, Folder 24)
    - Review of The Faber Book of War Poetry edited by Kenneth Baker (Box 36, Folder 25)
    - Review of Irish Birds by David Cabot (Box 36, Folder 26)
    - Review of More Latin Lyrics (Box 36, Folder 27)
    - Review of A Time to Speak by Helen Lewis (Box 36, Folder 28)
    - Review of William John Leech: An Irish Painter Abroad by Denis Ferran (Box 36, Folder 29)
    - Roundhead and Cavalier: The Poetry of John Hewitt and W. R. Rodgers (Box 36, Folder 30)
    - Sibelius (Box 36, Folder 31)
    - Tongue at Play, A, galley proofs (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Trinity College, Dublin, honorary D.Phil. [notes] (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Tuppenny Stung TS [includes Tuppeny Stung, The Empty Holes of Spring, Blackthorn & Bonsai, River & Fountain] (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Turning in their Graves or The Haunting of Garron Tower (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Twelfth of July, The [The First and the Twelfth of July] (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Two Peace Poems and a Few Thoughts about them (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Ulster Poetry (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Walking Forwards into the Past (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Weaver's Skill, The [review of Tales from Ovid, by Ted Hughes] (Box 37, Folder 9)